Azmine Toushik Wasi

+880 1521 526792 | <u>azminetoushik.wasi@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Facebook</u> | <u>Kaggle</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Website</u>

Summery

An idealist with distinguished experience, and expertise in Programming, IT Automation, Design, Ed-Tech, Product & Content Development and Project Management. Currently, exploring Data Science, Machine Learning and IT Automation. Love to learn new things, improve existing skills, experiment with acquired skills and challenge my capabilities.

Education

Feb 2020 - Present

Bachelor of Science (Engr.) in Industrial and Production
Engineering
Shahjalal University Of Science And Technology

Expected to complete in 2024

Work Experience

Mar 2022 - Present
Started working here
at Jun 2021

Project Executive - 10 Minute School (Part time)

Content quality, performance and distribution analytics
Team Lead, Content Design, 10 Minute School- Jobs

Sep 2021 - Feb 2022

Live-Class Resource Executive - Shikho (Part time)

• Preparation and quality 500+ Live-Class materials.

Content and performance analytics.

Organizational/Voluntary Experience

Sep 2022 – Jan 2022
Started working here
at Nov 2020

• Lead, Micro-course and App Product Development
• Regular technical R&D and improvements.

Sep 2021 – Feb 2022

Judge, The Queen's Commonwealth Essay Competition
2021 – Royal Commonwealth Society

 Member of the judging panel of the competition with 26.000+ submission

Sep 2019 – Present Online Volunteer - United Nations Volunteers

Data, Translation, Design and consulting based projects

Mar 2019 – Oct 2021 Information Technology Manager - Bangladesh Youngster Social Organization

 Developed App, Website and other IT Structures for the organization and increased productivity by 350%.

Technical Skills

Programming Skills: Python, R, C

Data Related Skills: Excel, PowerBI, Tableau, SAS Visual Business Analytics, SQL,

NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Machine Learning Skills: Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, Pycaret

Other Skills

Data Analytics, Visualization, Microsoft Word – Powerpoint - Access, Google Tools, Communication, Team Management, Teamwork, Proficient in Bangla and English

Virtual Internships

Aug 2021	 Data Analytics Internship EntryLevel Data Analytics , Business Modeling Used MS Excel, Power BI
Jun 2021	 Engineering: Undergraduate & Masters Forage - Microsoft Software Engineering, Design, Engineering thinking Data Analytics, Business Modeling
Mar 2021	 Data@ANZ Program Forage - ANZ Data Science (Used Scikitlearn - Linear Regression) Exploratory Data Analysis - Predictive Analytics
Apr 2021	 Open-Access Data Science & Advanced Analytics Forage BCG Data Science and Problem Structuring EDA, Feature Engineering, Mathematical Modeling

Prizes and Awards

GDN Presenta - Champion | Podiam 1.0 - 2nd Runners Up National High School Programming Contest - 2016 and 2017 - Regional Winner; National Top 30 in both

Inter School & College Programming Contest '19 – **Regional (3rd) – National Top 30**Queens Commonwealth Essay Competition 2019 – **Silver Award**National Earth Science Olympiad 2019 – **National Winner**Bangladesh Physics Olympiad 2019 Comilla Region – **5th**

Learning and Certifications

<u>Professional Certificates (Coursera):</u>

- DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer
- SAS Visual Business Analytics

<u>Google Career - Professional</u> <u>Certificates (Coursera):</u>

- Data Analyst
- IT Automation with Python
- IT Support Professional
- Project Management

Edx Courses:

- IBMx DS0105EN: Data Science Tools
- Harvardx PH526x: Using Python for Research

Coursera Specializations Completed:

- Python 3 Programming
- Applied Data Science with Python
- Data Analysis and Visualization

<u>DataCamp Learning Paths Completed:</u>

- Career Tracks: Python Programmer,
- <u>Skill Tracks</u>: Machine Learning Scientist with Python, Python Programming, Python Fundamentals
- Python Advanced Level Proficiency
 DataCamp Certified

<u>LinkedIn Learning Paths Completed:</u>

- Software Developer
- Data Analyst
- Financial Analyst

<u>IBM Developer Skills Network</u> <u>Programs:</u>

- Data and AI CP4D Journey Intermediate
- Python for Data Science Program

Frecodecamp.org Certifications:

Data Analysis with Python